six days in, six days in, what should I trade those?
Well, I can hold it then, I'm kind of sorry.
I don't know about the reasons.
But I have a full load of order, the amount of special utility
that's worth about me for Monday, December 19th.
I'm engaged in, but part of you, from the right.
Which breath me please.
God, I thank you for this day, and I thank you for each person here.
I ask God that you bless the decisions that are made tonight
and the people that make them.
I thank you, God, most of all, for this season that we can celebrate the birth of your son.
And it's his name, I pray.
Amen.
Well, I've always believed to the flag of the United States of America,
and two years later, you've got to let perwins just say,
one nation under God, an individual with liberty and justice for all.
Four public inputters, scheduled personal taxes, five,
the same as in the staff.
It means we approve out of six and seven.
Shall we move?
Second.
Five.
Eight.
Budget amendment.
I'm Mr. Geofil.
So this budget amendment is the second part of a two-part amendment.
So we're kind of doing a little bit backwards because of the meetings.
During the budget, the council approved for community.
I'm sorry.
Code compliance to purchase two SUVs.
After that, community development,
transferred a vehicle to code compliance, which leave them,
left them leading one, but now code,
that community development needed a vehicle.
So what we're doing is allowing code compliance,
and community development to both have a new vehicle,
new SUV.
And this is moving that money to do that to MSUA.
Well, let me make sure I get this straight.
We have a proof to get two new vehicles for code compliance.
Yes.
So, did does get purchased?
They got there in the middle.
They're getting purchased.
We have heard, and we guys have heard as community animals,
we felt that the cars were surfacing on code compliance vehicles.
But we transferred by and of the community,
we didn't know what vehicle was able to do.
So this is not new money.
No, this is a chance.
Just a transfer.
Do we even need to vote on that?
Yes.
Well, apparently we do because they're here again.
I mean, they already belong to the city, can you have a big transfer of right?
Yes.
So in the budget, in the budget, message, you approve for the city manager to be able to move
money inside of funds.
So in 510, he can move money around with his approval.
We can do that with his approval.
But to move money from fund to fund is a council approval.
This is moving money in fund to fund.
Yeah, Kevin.
I'll make a motion.
I'll second it.
All right.
Thank you.
No, we have to grab the Edmunds and Palmer Cunningham for a GRDA, a licensing in the
amount of $4,359.89.
So I'm going to take the opportunity and kind of really talk about items 9 and 10.
Since they both, you'll need to vote on separately, but they aren't related in the sense
that they're both regarding and the licensing and the update study report that GRDA done.
And that DWT have participated in as well as the good El Stratton as well as Tectrotec who
does all of the modeling, the river 2D modeling.
And so what been his handing out is I just wanted to show you all because we kind of have
these conversations around in and I know it's a lot of dollar amounts and a lot of dates that
get really confusing.
And so I thought I'd kind of let you look at it all at once.
But what if you're looking at it's down at the bottom on the far left and says 12 19 and there's
two of those.
Those are the two that you're actually looking at tonight.
That's 9 and 10.
I'll be in gender.
But you can see the overall impact, the 750,000 dollar budget on the far right as we've gone through
this fiscal year.
Those are the different claims that we've had applied to that 750,000.
So after tonight, if you approve those two invoices to be paid, our remaining budget would
be 613,388 and then I also wanted to put on there an invoice that will be coming at the next
council meeting, which will be the third of January.
This one did not come in time to make it on this.
So putting it on for the next one.
And so it was 69,000, but I didn't want to just string that one on you after having a rather
large one tonight and enter around another large one next month and not really have an explanation
or have some visibility of a totality of what it looks like.
But if you look at the dates of service, you can see that they span different times.
And the reason that those ones are big is they're all dealing with either prep or the
studying report.
the technical conference on the 12th and 13th of October, or it was in response to that,
which we had to huddle up and do a very lengthy response, which was after that.
It says, those are what you're seeing in those rather large, so what we're going to see
now is probably a pretty good decline for a little while, as we're working on some other
items.
Even talking about maybe doing another town hall for the first year sometime, so we'll probably
have some gear up for that, but other than that, just kind of want to give you an overall
visibility of what that looked like against the 70 or 50,000.
So question, this should you remember modeling, is that going to be data that we own?
That's our data?
Yes, absolutely.
And will there be somebody that did this work or study, be able to put this data in Laman's
terms that our average Joe citizen will be able to understand, I mean, obviously, I'd like
to know.
Absolutely, I actually had a conversation with Diet Thomas who did news responsible for
going to the modeling.
And we talked about him possibly coming to my mind in presenting that data, which he was really
excited to do to get that opportunity to come present the data in the town hall meeting.
I think if we were having a town hall and we could present this in a manner that people would
understand it would be very beneficial.
I couldn't agree more.
I think more than anything I think this would be.
I think we need to really see the data, but also after, after our last meeting, Mr. Jim was
here, and kind of asked us all the questions up here.
I talked to our law team and asked them if we could set aside a time that we could meet.
And you guys could ask questions that you may get from your constituents, so you would know
the answers to give.
I think that's probably pretty important.
Especially after we heard, you know, so I was didn't know the answers to the thing.
I mean, I didn't honestly have any, I've never had anybody come at me.
So any response I would have got would have been my own opinion on it and feel it was appropriate to
provide that in that setting.
But anyway, we're trying to set up for us to build the debate with him as well.
And be good.
I like that.
And when you look on here in the description, you'll see a couple of things.
It says, will curb change.
You know, it says, Pinsicle, it relies on things.
Ultimately, it does mean the same thing.
It's just how each attorney perceives it and what their role is.
Pinsicle, it relies on things related to the broker that they are requesting to change.
It's 700,000 and we've only used roughly 100,000 in this debate.
I do.
You know, I looked at last year in last year, I would say it was fairly similar in the way that
the year rolled out with the technical conferences.
And so it was kind of similar that we had spent about 150,000.
Then we ended up spending about 450,000 or so after.
the counter, counter, counter, you start it over.
But we had a meeting there today with the attorneys and we were kind of laying out what
looked like between now and the end of the fiscal year.
I don't think it's going to be quite the heavy lift.
This fiscal year, the remaining six months, is it was the second six months of the last
fiscal year or so?
I think we're ahead of the game.
Is there a deadline on this re-licensing?
Do you already have a certain timeline that they have to have this re-licensing done by?
So it's scheduled right now to be done in 2025 and we've been standing there.
We've had was extended to 2025.
And as Ben and I were talking this morning, it wouldn't be unheard of for them for
GRDA to request it to be extended to the end.
There was one instance where the re-licensing obviously unrelated to ours, but it was extended
for a total of 30 years.
During which time they operated under the license that existed at the time.
Do they are able to get any kind of waivers to operate under the new term that they're looking
for right?
No.
My understanding is that it has to be under the terms of the old licenses long as it's being extended.
The correct one from the wrong here, Ben.
Better even follow the rules of the old license.
Great.
Well, there's lawsuit asking that question.
But that kind of extension is very rare.
I mean, it's not unusual for a five to 10-year extension, but a 30-year is very rare.
So again, it was interesting that, you know, I talked about the fact that we had to
reply to the last study, update, study report.
And for also wrote their reply and it was really good to see all the entities that submitted.
We all had kind of similar concerns.
So I would tell you, it is, I am optimistic when you see her having the same concerns.
That's a good sign.
And they had submitted their four hours before we submitted ours.
It wasn't like they saw ours and so yeah.
No.
It seems like there is a time frame in which the RDA has to respond to that.
December 29th is a date for some reason.
So it could be the response time.
Because we had to file them by the end of November.
So they probably have to leave them to December to respond.
Yeah.
And the real licensing process that we'll find, I don't want to ask about the two feet last week.
And the real licensing, they're asking for two more feet.
Right.
So that's why we have to be diligent.
We have to stay on top of this.
We need to be evaluating.
every step of this study process because this is a fifty-year license, right?
Is it fifty-year license that the RDA has requested?
Some of it once perk makes a determination and that license is granted or not created.
That could be an effect for thirty-four-y-fifty years.
So we got to live with whatever happened.
Well, we know.
Our great-grandkids.
The very great kids in the hands.
It's a long time.
So, Rob Nye.
I don't know what it means.
I would marry anyone.
The client, for the Nobel Prize, or the patents in the palm.
I make a motion we approve nine?
10?
Ten?
Detrotate a client for a Neosho River, a two-day modelling for the amount of thirty-six thousand
three hundred dollars.
Make a motion we approve this month.
Tak.
Ten?
Five.
Eleven will be tables.
Twelve.
There'll be business, if anyone's as a residence in the post office.
the citizens of the posting of this agenda, 13 staff reports, 14 community, or trustee
community in Dallaswood, 15. This may be continued from California to the state of the
State of Dallaswood, the birth of purpose and executive session at the completion of
the agenda item, 15 of the regular meeting through the moment of city council.